[{"text": "Harry Potter is a series of seven children's fantasy novels written by British author J.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8939}, {"word": "British", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9997}]}, {"text": "The novels chronicle the lives of a young wizard, Harry Potter, and his friends, Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger, among others, all of whom are students at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Ron Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Hermione Granger", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9274}]}, {"text": "The main story arc concerns Harry's conflict with Lord Voldemort, a dark wizard who intends to become immortal, overthrow the wizard governing body known as the Ministry of Magic, and subjugate all wizards and non-magical people, known in-universe as Muggles.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9871}, {"word": "Ministry of Magic", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9977}]}, {"text": "The series was originally published in English by Bloomsbury in the United Kingdom and Scholastic Press in the United States.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "English", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Bloomsbury", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9965}, {"word": "United Kingdom", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Scholastic Press", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "United States", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9994}]}, {"text": "A series of many genres, including fantasy, drama, coming-of-age fiction, and the British school story (which includes elements of mystery, thriller, adventure, horror, and romance), the world of Harry Potter explores numerous themes and includes many cultural meanings and references.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "British", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9998}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9159}]}, {"text": "Major themes in the series include prejudice, corruption, madness, love, and death.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": []}, {"text": "Since the release of the first novel, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, on 26 June 1997, the books have found immense popularity and commercial success worldwide.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9533}]}, {"text": "They have attracted a wide adult audience as well as younger readers and are widely considered cornerstones of modern literature, though the books have received mixed reviews from critics and literary scholars.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": []}, {"text": "As of February 2023, the books have sold more than 600 million copies worldwide, making them the best-selling book series in history, available in dozens of languages.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": []}, {"text": "The last four books all set records as the fastest-selling books in history, with the final instalment selling roughly 2.7 million copies in the United Kingdom and 8.3 million copies in the United States within twenty-four hours of its release.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "United Kingdom", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "United States", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9995}]}, {"text": "Pictures adapted the original seven books into an eight-part namesake film series.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": []}, {"text": "In 2016, the total value of the Harry Potter franchise was estimated at $25 billion, making it one of the highest-grossing media franchises of all time.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9062}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Cursed Child is a play based on a story co-written by Rowling.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter and the Cursed Child", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9362}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}]}, {"text": "A television series based on the books is in production at HBO.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "HBO", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9955}]}, {"text": "The success of the books and films has allowed the Harry Potter franchise to expand with numerous derivative works, a travelling exhibition that premiered in Chicago in 2009, a studio tour in London that opened in 2012, a digital platform on which J.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9824}, {"word": "Chicago", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "London", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9997}]}, {"text": "Rowling updates the series with new information and insight, and a trilogy of spin-off films premiering in November 2016 with Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them, among many other developments.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Fantastic Beasts", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9727}, {"word": "Where to Find Them", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8221}]}, {"text": "Themed attractions, collectively known as The Wizarding World of Harry Potter, have been built at several Universal Destinations & Experiences amusement parks around the world.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "The Wizarding World of Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9936}, {"word": "Universal Destinations & Experiences", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9842}]}, {"text": "Plot\n\nEarly years\n\nThe series follows the life of a boy named Harry Potter.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9966}]}, {"text": "In the first book, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone in the US), Harry lives in a cupboard under the stairs in the house of the Dursleys, his aunt, uncle and cousin, who all treat him poorly.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9252}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the Sorcerer ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.852}, {"word": "US", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}]}, {"text": "At the age of 11, Harry discovers that he is a wizard.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "He meets a half-giant named Hagrid who gives him a letter of acceptance to attend the Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Hagrid", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}, {"word": "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.7939}]}, {"text": "Harry learns that his parents, Lily and James Potter, also had magical powers and were murdered by the dark wizard Lord Voldemort when Harry was a baby.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}, {"word": "Lily", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "James Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9521}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9962}]}, {"text": "When Voldemort attempted to kill Harry, his curse rebounded, seemingly killing Voldemort, and Harry survived with a lightning-shaped scar on his forehead.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9959}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "The event made Harry famous among the community of wizards and witches.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}]}, {"text": "Harry becomes a student at Hogwarts and is sorted into Gryffindor House.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9692}, {"word": "Gryffindor House", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8976}]}, {"text": "He gains the friendship of Ron Weasley, a member of a large but poor wizarding family, and Hermione Granger, a witch of non-magical, or Muggle, parentage.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Ron Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Hermione Granger", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}]}, {"text": "The trio develop an enmity with the rich pure-blood student Draco Malfoy.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Draco Malfoy", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}]}, {"text": "Harry encounters the school's headmaster, Albus Dumbledore; the potions professor, Severus Snape, who displays a dislike for him; and the Defence Against the Dark Arts teacher, Quirinus Quirrell.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9981}, {"word": "Albus Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Severus Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Defence Against the Dark Arts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9695}, {"word": "Quirinus Quirrell", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "Quirrell turns out to be allied with Voldemort, who is still alive as a weak spirit.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Quirrell", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9881}]}, {"text": "The first book concludes with Harry's confrontation with Voldemort, who, in his quest to regain a body, yearns to possess the Philosopher's Stone, a substance that bestows everlasting life.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9977}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7737}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets describes Harry's second year at Hogwarts.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9904}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9821}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9941}]}, {"text": "Students are attacked and petrified by an unknown creature; wizards of Muggle parentage are the primary targets.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9935}]}, {"text": "The attacks appear related to the mythical Chamber of Secrets and resemble attacks fifty years earlier.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9233}]}, {"text": "Harry discovers an ability to speak the snake language Parseltongue, which he learns is rare and associated with the Dark Arts.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Parseltongue", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.867}, {"word": "Dark Arts", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.991}]}, {"text": "When Hermione is attacked and Ron's younger sister Ginny Weasley is abducted, Harry and Ron uncover the chamber's secrets and enter it.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9967}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Ginny Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9963}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}]}, {"text": "Harry discovers that Ginny was possessed by an old diary, inside which the memory of Tom Marvolo Riddle, Voldemort's younger self, resides.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Ginny", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9974}, {"word": "Tom Marvolo Riddle", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}]}, {"text": "On Voldemort's behalf, Ginny opened the chamber and unleashed the basilisk, an ancient monster that kills or petrifies those who make direct or indirect eye contact, respectively.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9839}, {"word": "Ginny", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.997}]}, {"text": "With the help of Dumbledore's phoenix, Fawkes, and the Sword of Gryffindor, Harry slays the basilisk and destroys the diary.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9269}, {"word": "Fawkes", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9939}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9976}]}, {"text": "In the third novel, Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, Harry learns that he is targeted by Sirius Black, an escaped convict who allegedly assisted in his parents' murder.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9107}, {"word": "of", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7872}, {"word": "Azkaban", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.8591}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Sirius Black", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "Dementors, creatures that feed on happiness, search for Sirius and guard the school.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Sirius", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9864}]}, {"text": "As Harry struggles with his reaction to the dementors, he reaches out to Remus Lupin, a new professor who teaches him the Patronus charm.", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Remus Lupin", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9966}]}, {"text": "On a windy night, Ron is dragged by a black dog into the", "source": "Harry Potter", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}]}, {"text": "Hermione Granger ( hur-MY-ə-nee GRAYN-jər) is a fictional character in the Harry Potter series of novels by J.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione Granger", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9973}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9518}]}, {"text": "She first appeared in Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (1997) as a first-year student on her way to Hogwarts, a school of magic.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9901}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9958}]}, {"text": "In the novel, she becomes friends with Harry Potter and Ron Weasley after they save her from a troll.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Ron Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}]}, {"text": "Hermione often uses her quick wit, deft recall, and encyclopaedic knowledge to help her friends in perilous situations.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9854}]}, {"text": "Rowling has stated that Hermione resembles herself as a young girl.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.997}]}, {"text": "Hermione is portrayed by Emma Watson in all eight Harry Potter films, and is set to be played by Arabella Stanton in the upcoming television series.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9922}, {"word": "Emma Watson", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8437}, {"word": "Arabella Stanton", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "Character\nRowling has described Hermione as a strong female character who is bright, logical, upright, and good.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.996}]}, {"text": "Rowling was seen as a \"know-it-all\" in her youth, and she said Hermione is an exaggerated version of her younger self.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.988}]}, {"text": "She says that beneath Hermione's studious and sometimes bossy exterior, she is insecure and afraid of failure, similar to Rowling as a young person.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9936}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "Rowling said that to compensate for her feelings of inadequacy, Hermione strives to be the best at everything; she projects a confidence that irritates others.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9961}]}, {"text": "In the novels, Hermione is described as having bushy brown hair, brown eyes and large front teeth.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9984}]}, {"text": "She is described as an exceptionally talented witch, and Rowling has called her a \"borderline genius\".", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}]}, {"text": "Watson said that girls in popular media tend to \"dumb themselves down\", but Hermione is not afraid to be clever, which makes her an exceptional role model for girls.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Watson", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9981}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}]}, {"text": "Freier has noted that, throughout the Harry Potter series, Hermione uses the skills of a librarian and researcher to gather the information needed to defeat Voldemort.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Freier", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9761}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9961}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.985}]}, {"text": "Freier observes that Hermione begins the series as a child \"who loves the library but cannot always use it effectively\", relying on the Hogwarts school librarian for help.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Freier", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9979}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.913}]}, {"text": "However, as the series progresses Hermione becomes a librarian herself, according to Freier.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9965}, {"word": "Freier", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}]}, {"text": "Rowling has called Hermione the perfect expository character due to her encyclopaedic knowledge of the wizarding world.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9971}]}, {"text": "Rowling has described Hermione's classmate Luna Lovegood as the \"anti-Hermione\" due to the differences between them.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9937}, {"word": "Luna Lovegood", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "Hermione's first name was derived from a character in William Shakespeare's The Winter's Tale, although according to Rowling the two characters have little in common.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9686}, {"word": "William Shakespeare", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "The Winter ' s Tale", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9976}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}]}, {"text": "Hermione's middle name was originally Jane, but Rowling changed it to Jean so Hermione would not have the same middle name as Dolores Jane Umbridge.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.994}, {"word": "Jane", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Jean", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9969}, {"word": "Dolores Jane Umbridge", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9966}]}, {"text": "Rowling considered giving Hermione the surname \"Puckle\", but ultimately felt the name did not suit her.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9973}, {"word": "Puckle", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.987}]}, {"text": "Rowling said that Hermione's parents, two Muggle dentists, are somewhat bemused by their \"odd\" daughter, but are proud of her nonetheless; they are the type of people who would give their daughter an unusual name to prove their cleverness.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9951}, {"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9785}]}, {"text": "Hermione is proud of her Muggle heritage and, according to Rowling, she works at the Ministry of Magic after graduation from Hogwarts, advocating for disenfranchised populations such as House-elves and Muggle-borns.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.992}, {"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9914}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Ministry of Magic", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.982}, {"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9934}]}, {"text": "Hermione's Patronus is an otter, which is Rowling's favourite animal.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.935}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}]}, {"text": "Appearances\n\nNovels\n\nHarry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\nHermione is introduced in Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (1997) when she meets Harry Potter and Ron Weasley on the Hogwarts Express.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9702}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.952}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.968}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Ron Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8597}]}, {"text": "After mocking Ron for his inability to perform a spell, she proves her knowledge by declaring that she has memorized all their school textbooks.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}]}, {"text": "At Hogwarts, Hermione annoys other students with her vast knowledge, and Harry and Ron consider her arrogant.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.96}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9948}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "They heartily dislike her until they rescue her from a troll; she is so thankful that she lies to protect them from punishment, thus winning their friendship.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": []}, {"text": "Later, Hermione's knack for logic and her penchant for library research aid the trio in their quest to locate a magical object known as the Philosopher's Stone.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9862}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8313}]}, {"text": "On their way to the Stone, Hermione solves a puzzle and defeats the dangerous Devil's Snare plant.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9802}]}, {"text": "Rowling said she resisted requests by her editor to remove the troll scene.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}]}, {"text": "She explained that due to Hermione's arrogance and irritating personality during the beginning of the first novel, something \"huge\" was needed to catalyze her friendship with Harry and Ron.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9956}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets\nIn Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (1998), Hermione develops a liking for Gilderoy Lockhart, the new Defence Against the Dark Arts professor.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.7544}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9607}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8764}, {"word": "the Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.807}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9954}, {"word": "Gilderoy Lockhart", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Defence Against the Dark Arts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9845}]}, {"text": "During a confrontation between the Gryffindor and Slytherin Quidditch teams, a brawl nearly ensues after Draco Malfoy calls her a \"Mudblood\", an insulting term for a Muggle-born wizard.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Gryffindor", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8491}, {"word": "Draco Malfoy", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9964}, {"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9933}]}, {"text": "Hermione concocts a Polyjuice Potion so she, Harry and Ron can infiltrate the Slytherin dormitory and collect information about the Heir of Slytherin.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9632}, {"word": "Polyjuice Potion", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9511}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Slytherin", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9429}, {"word": "Slytherin", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9775}]}, {"text": "The boys drink the potion and take on the appearance of Malfoy's friends, but Hermione, having used a cat hair in her vial of potion, ends up looking like a cat and cannot join the mission.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Malfoy", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9915}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9949}]}, {"text": "When a basilisk escapes from the Chamber of Secrets, Hermione successfully identifies it through library research, but is Petrified by its reflection.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9715}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9917}]}, {"text": "Though she lies incapacitated in the hospital wing, the information she found aids Harry and Ron in their quest to solve the mystery of the Chamber.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Chamber", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.7476}]}, {"text": "Hermione is revived after Harry kills the basilisk, but is distraught to learn that all end-of-year exams have been cancelled.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9776}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban\nIn Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (1999), Hermione buys a cat named Crookshanks, who takes to chasing Ron's pet rat, Scabbers.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.988}, {"word": "of Azkaban", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7118}, {"word": "Harry Potter and", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9073}, {"word": "Prisoner of Azkaban", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9116}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9933}, {"word": "Crookshanks", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.927}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Scabbers", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9319}]}, {"text": "Before the start of term, McGonagall secretly gives Hermione a Time-Turner, a device which lets her travel through time to handle her busy class schedule.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "McGonagall", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9981}, {"word": "Time - Turner", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.986}]}, {"text": "During the school year, tension arises between Hermione and her two best friends.", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9959}]}, {"text": "Harry becomes furious with her because she told McG", "source": "Hermione Granger", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9984}]}, {"text": "Ronald Weasley is a fictional character in the Harry Potter series of novels by J.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ronald Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8562}]}, {"text": "He is introduced in Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone as a first-year student on his way to Hogwarts, a school of magic.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.7351}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9792}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9914}]}, {"text": "During the school year, Ron befriends Harry Potter and Hermione Granger.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Hermione Granger", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9976}]}, {"text": "Being the only member of the trio who was raised in wizarding society, he provides insight into wizarding customs and traditions.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": []}, {"text": "Along with Harry and Hermione, he is a member of Gryffindor House at Hogwarts and is present for most of the action throughout the series.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9959}, {"word": "Gryffindor House", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9079}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9937}]}, {"text": "Ron is portrayed by Rupert Grint in all eight Harry Potter films, and will be played by Alastair Stout in the upcoming television series.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Rupert Grint", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9998}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8329}, {"word": "Alastair Stout", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}]}, {"text": "Creation and development\nRon was one of the first Harry Potter characters that Rowling created.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9159}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}]}, {"text": "Although Ron and Hermione form a romantic bond in the series and eventually have children, Rowling confessed in a 2014 interview that she wrote the relationship as \"a form of wish fulfilment\".", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9948}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}]}, {"text": "She said the characters are fundamentally incompatible in some ways, but that their relationship might function with \"a bit of counselling\".", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": []}, {"text": "Appearances\n\nNovels\n\nHarry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\nRon is introduced in the first novel in the series, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (1997).", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.8813}, {"word": "the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9295}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.955}]}, {"text": "He and his family encounter Harry Potter at King's Cross station and help him find the Hogwarts Express.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "King ' s Cross", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9897}, {"word": "Hogwarts Express", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9642}]}, {"text": "Once aboard the train, Ron and Harry meet Hermione Granger, whom they initially dislike.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Hermione Granger", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9969}]}, {"text": "At Hogwarts, all three students are assigned to Gryffindor House.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9807}, {"word": "Gryffindor House", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.7417}]}, {"text": "After Ron and Harry save Hermione from a troll, they develop a friendship with her.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.988}]}, {"text": "When the trio seeks the Philosopher's Stone, Ron uses his skill at Wizard's Chess to allow Harry and Hermione to proceed safely through a dangerous, life-sized chess game.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9583}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Wizard ' s Chess", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9976}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9681}]}, {"text": "At the last dinner of the school year, the Hogwarts headmaster Albus Dumbledore rewards Ron's chess skill by giving him fifty House points, which helps Gryffindor win the House Cup.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.971}, {"word": "Albus Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "House", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.7102}, {"word": "Gryffindor", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.922}, {"word": "House Cup", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.993}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets\nRon returns in Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (1998).", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9718}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9827}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9592}, {"word": "the", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7844}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8945}]}, {"text": "During the summer after his first year at Hogwarts, Ron writes to Harry several times.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9475}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "He receives no answer because his letters are intercepted by Dobby the house-elf.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Dobby", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "Ron becomes so concerned that he and his brothers Fred and George fly to Harry's house in their father's enchanted car.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Fred", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "George", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}]}, {"text": "Harry spends the next month at the Weasleys' home.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}]}, {"text": "When Harry and Ron are unable to board the train to Hogwarts, they take the flying car instead.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9984}]}, {"text": "Ron receives a Howler from his mother, who berates him for taking the car.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}]}, {"text": "Later in the novel, Ron and Harry use Polyjuice Potion to disguise themselves as they infiltrate the Slytherin dormitory and attempt to gather information about the Chamber of Secrets.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Slytherin", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.8919}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8959}]}, {"text": "During a journey into the Forbidden Forest, Ron is forced to encounter his worst nightmare: spiders.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Forbidden Forest", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9973}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}]}, {"text": "The giant arachnids nearly devour Ron and Harry, but the enchanted car rescues them.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}]}, {"text": "Ron and Harry then enter the Chamber to save Ron's sister Ginny, who was kidnapped.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Ginny", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}]}, {"text": "After Harry rescues her, both boys are given awards for their service to Hogwarts.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.8086}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban\nIn Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (1999), Ron's pet rat Scabbers goes missing.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9927}, {"word": "Harry Potter and", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7971}, {"word": "Prisoner of Azkaban", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8263}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Scabbers", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9685}]}, {"text": "Ron, Harry and Hermione eventually discover him hiding in Hagrid's hut.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9892}, {"word": "Hagrid", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9977}]}, {"text": "When Scabbers runs off again, Ron chases him to the Whomping Willow, where he is snatched by a large black dog and dragged into a tunnel.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Scabbers", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9684}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Whomping", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8485}]}, {"text": "Ron and his friends follow the tunnel to the Shrieking Shack.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Shrieking Shack", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.817}]}, {"text": "The dog turns out to be Sirius Black, who explains that Scabbers is actually the Death Eater Peter Pettigrew.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Sirius Black", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.998}, {"word": "Scabbers", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9836}, {"word": "Death", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8677}, {"word": "Peter Pettigrew", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}]}, {"text": "As Ron returns to Hogwarts with Harry, Hermione, Sirius and Remus Lupin, Pettigrew knocks Ron unconscious and escapes.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9871}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9979}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.988}, {"word": "Sirius", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9967}, {"word": "Remus Lupin", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.976}, {"word": "Pettigrew", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}]}, {"text": "Ron is forced to remain in the hospital wing of Hogwarts while Harry and Hermione travel back in time to rescue Sirius and the hippogriff Buckbeak.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9718}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9877}, {"word": "Sirius", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9939}, {"word": "Buckbeak", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9862}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire\nThe Weasleys invite Harry and Hermione to the Quidditch World Cup in Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire (2000).", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9923}, {"word": "Goblet of Fire", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9681}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9763}, {"word": "Quidditch World Cup", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.998}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8559}, {"word": "the Goblet of Fire", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8732}]}, {"text": "Ron is in awe when he sees his favourite Quidditch player, Viktor Krum.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Viktor Krum", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}]}, {"text": "He is even more excited when Krum comes to Hogwarts to participate in the Triwizard Tournament.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Krum", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.996}, {"word": "Triwizard Tournament", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9971}]}, {"text": "At Christmas time, Ron attends the Yule Ball with Padma Patil.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Yule Ball", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9789}, {"word": "Padma Patil", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}]}, {"text": "He becomes very upset when he sees that Hermione's date to the Ball is Krum, and the two have a heated argument.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9953}, {"word": "Ball", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.912}, {"word": "Krum", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}]}, {"text": "In the second task of the Tournament, Harry must rescue Ron from the depths of the Hogwarts lake.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Tournament", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7713}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9915}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix\nIn Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix (2003), Ron is made a Gryffindor prefect.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9932}, {"word": "Order of the Phoenix", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9408}, {"word": "Order of the Phoenix", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.7888}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}]}, {"text": "His brother Percy congratulates him and advises him to become an ally of Dolores Umbridge, the new Defence Against the Dark Arts professor appointed by the Ministry of Magic.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Percy", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Dolores Umbridge", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Defence Against the Dark Arts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Ministry of Magic", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.999}]}, {"text": "Ron, however, does not support Umbridge's policy of refusing to teach students practical defensive magic.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Umbridge", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9956}]}, {"text": "He, Harry and Hermione form the group Dumebledore's Army, which provides a venue for students to practise defensive spellcasting.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9932}, {"word": "Dumebledore", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8525}, {"word": "s Army", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.7071}]}, {"text": "Ron also joins the Gryffindor Quidditch team as Keeper and helps Gryffindor win the Quidditch Cup.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Gryffindor Quidditch", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9907}, {"word": "Gryffindor", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9767}, {"word": "Quidditch Cup", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.997}]}, {"text": "Near the end of the novel, Ron battles Death Eaters at the Department of Mysteries alongside Harry, Hermione, Ginny, Neville Longbottom and Luna Lovegood.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Death Eaters", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9838}, {"word": "Department of Mysteries", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9985}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9963}, {"word": "Ginny", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Neville Longbottom", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Luna Lovegood", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}]}, {"text": "He is injured during the fight, but makes a full recovery.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": []}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince\nRon returns as Quidditch Keeper in Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince (2005).", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9941}, {"word": "Half - Blood Prince", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8438}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7652}, {"word": "Half - Blood Prince", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9012}]}, {"text": "However, he performs poorly at Quidditch after learning that Hermione may have kissed Krum.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Quidditch", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9584}, {"word": "Hermione", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9966}, {"word": "Krum", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}]}, {"text": "He becomes upset when he observes his younger sister Ginny kissing a boy, and Ginny reacts by pointing out that Ron has never been kissed.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ginny", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Ginny", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}]}, {"text": "To bolster Ron's confidence for an upcoming Quidditch match, Harry pretends to give him a luck potion.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Quidditch", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8787}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}]}, {"text": "Believing he has actually taken the potion, Ron performs well and Gryffindor wins the match.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Gryffindor", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.995}]}, {"text": "During the ensuing celebration, Ron kisses Lavender Brown.", "source": "Ron Weasley", "entities": [{"word": "Ron", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Lavender Brown", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9919}]}, {"text": "Albus Dumbledore is a fictional character in the Harry Potter series of novels by J.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Albus Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7689}]}, {"text": "For most of the series, he is the headmaster of the wizarding school Hogwarts.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9316}]}, {"text": "He is one of the most powerful and influential wizards of his time, and is the founder and leader of the Order of the Phoenix, an organisation dedicated to fighting the dark wizard Lord Voldemort.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Order of the Phoenix", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9811}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9243}]}, {"text": "Dumbledore is portrayed by Richard Harris in the film adaptations of Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (2001) and Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (2002).", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9882}, {"word": "Richard Harris", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8966}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9922}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9103}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9254}]}, {"text": "Following Harris' death in October 2002, Michael Gambon was cast in the role.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Harris", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Michael Gambon", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9998}]}, {"text": "He plays Dumbledore in six Harry Potter films, which were released from 2004 to 2011.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9955}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9612}]}, {"text": "Jude Law portrays a middle-aged version of Dumbledore in the prequel films Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald (2018) and Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore (2022).", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Jude Law", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9967}, {"word": "Fantastic Beasts", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9966}, {"word": "The Crimes of Grindelwald", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9417}, {"word": "Fantastic Beasts", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.996}, {"word": "The Secrets of Dumbledore", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8587}]}, {"text": "John Lithgow is set to portray Dumbledore in the upcoming HBO series Harry Potter.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "John Lithgow", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9998}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9971}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9617}]}, {"text": "Character\nIn a 1999 interview, Rowling stated that she imagined Dumbledore as elderly and stately, and compared him to John Gielgud.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "John Gielgud", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "In the novels, Dumbledore is described as tall and thin, with a long and crooked nose, long fingers and bright blue eyes.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9961}]}, {"text": "His hair and beard are described as long and silver.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "He wears half-moon spectacles and a colourful array of robes.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "In 2000, Rowling said that Dumbledore is a hundred and fifty years old during the events of the novels.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9953}]}, {"text": "However, she has stated on her website that he was born in 1881, which makes him either 115 or 116 when he dies in the sixth novel.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "Rowling has described Dumbledore as very wise and \"the epitome of goodness\".", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9966}]}, {"text": "She said he is a mentor to Harry Potter, and he knows that Harry will need to learn difficult lessons to prepare him for challenges in his life.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}]}, {"text": "According to Rowling, Dumbledore \"allows Harry to get into what he would not allow another pupil to do, and he also unwillingly permits Harry to confront things he'd rather protect him from.\" Dumbledore's demeanour is often described as serene, ethereal and composed, and he rarely displays strong emotions.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9945}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9943}]}, {"text": "He is eccentric, slightly effeminate and fond of knitting.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "He is known for his odd displays of whimsicality, and he often uses humour to put others at ease.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "His eyes are sometimes described as twinkling with kindness or mischief.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "Dumbledore is highly perceptive and emotionally intelligent, and has a deep capacity for love.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "Dumbledore's personality also has a more steely aspect.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "When he apprehends Barty Crouch Jr in Goblet of Fire, the look upon his face is described as full of \"cold fury\" and \"more terrible than Harry could have ever imagined.\"\nDumbledore is considered by many characters to be the most powerful wizard alive.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Barty Crouch Jr", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9963}, {"word": "Goblet of Fire", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9896}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9898}]}, {"text": "Some say he is the only wizard Voldemort ever feared.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9977}]}, {"text": "During his education at Hogwarts, Dumbledore was in Gryffindor House.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9458}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9966}, {"word": "Gryffindor House", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9285}]}, {"text": "He was the most brilliant student the school had ever known, winning \"every prize of note that the school offered\", and doing \"things with a wand [the examiner had] never seen before\".", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "Rowling has said that Dumbledore is primarily self-taught, although he \"had access to superb teachers at Hogwarts\".", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.8794}]}, {"text": "Dumbledore readily acknowledges that he is unusually intelligent and an exceptionally powerful wizard.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "He is skilled in Occlumency, Legilimency and Transfiguration, and is the owner of the powerful Elder Wand, which is one of the Deathly Hallows.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Wand", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7775}]}, {"text": "In spite of Dumbledore's many extraordinary qualities, he is a flawed character.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9903}]}, {"text": "According to Rowling, \"Although Dumbledore seems to be so benign for six books, he's quite a Machiavellian figure, really.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9946}, {"word": "Machiavellian", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9989}]}, {"text": "He's been pulling a lot of strings.\" In a 2005 interview, Rowling commented: \"Immense brainpower does not protect you from emotional mistakes, and I think Dumbledore really exemplifies that.\" In the novels, Dumbledore admits a number of times to Harry that he makes mistakes, and since he is smarter than most people, his mistakes \"tend to be correspondingly huger\".", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9952}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.997}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}]}, {"text": "Rowling has said that Dumbledore speaks for her, the author, as he knows almost everything about the Harry Potter universe.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9953}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9585}]}, {"text": "Dumbledore describes his desire for power as his greatest flaw.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "He eventually finds that those best suited for power are those who do not seek it.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "When he and Grindelwald first meet, they make plans to enslave Muggles and re-establish wizards as the natural rulers of the world.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Grindelwald", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.998}, {"word": "Muggles", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.7376}]}, {"text": "Dumbledore becomes disillusioned with this idea after his sister Ariana is killed during a duel between himself, his brother Aberforth, and Grindelwald.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9886}, {"word": "Ariana", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9959}, {"word": "Aberforth", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9933}, {"word": "Grindelwald", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9837}]}, {"text": "Dumbledore becomes riddled with guilt over the circumstances surrounding the death of his sister.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "He is tortured for the rest of his life by the possibility that he might have been the one who cast the spell that killed her.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "When he looks into the Mirror of Erised, he sees himself redeemed in the eyes of his brother and his entire family alive and together.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Mirror of Erised", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9081}]}, {"text": "The name \"Dumbledore\" is borrowed from a dialectal word for \"bumblebee\".", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "Rowling chose the name because Dumbledore loves music, and she imagined him walking around and humming to himself frequently.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9972}]}, {"text": "Appearances in novels\n\nHarry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\nDumbledore is introduced in the opening chapter of the first novel in the series, Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (1997).", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9527}, {"word": "the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8757}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9396}]}, {"text": "Under cover of night, he brings the infant Harry Potter to the home of Harry's uncle and aunt, Vernon and Petunia Dursley.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9968}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Vernon", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Petunia Dursley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9901}]}, {"text": "Harry's parents were killed by the Dark wizard Voldemort, and Dumbledore hopes he will be safe with the Dursleys.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Dark", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9903}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9972}]}, {"text": "He leaves Harry on the doorstep with a letter explaining the situation.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}]}, {"text": "When Harry arrives at Hogwarts ten years later, Dumbledore tells him about the Mirror of Erised, a magical object that protects the Philosopher's Stone.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9925}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.991}, {"word": "Mirror of Erised", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9634}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7558}]}, {"text": "Dumbledore is summoned to the Ministry of Magic by a false message on the night when Harry, Ron Weasley, Hermione Granger, and Professor Quirinus Quirrell enter the dungeons to retrieve the Stone.", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9836}, {"word": "Ministry of Magic", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9978}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Ron Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Hermione Granger", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Quirinus Quirrell", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}]}, {"text": "He realises during the trip that he is needed", "source": "Albus Dumbledore", "entities": []}, {"text": "Lord Voldemort ( VOHL-də-mor, -⁠mort in the films) is a fictional character and the main antagonist in the Harry Potter series of novels by J.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Lord Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.8326}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7775}]}, {"text": "He first appears in Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone (1997) and returns either in person or in flashbacks in each novel in the series except the third, Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban, in which he is only mentioned.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.967}, {"word": "Prisoner of", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9363}, {"word": "Azkaban", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.8878}]}, {"text": "Lord Voldemort—where \"I am Lord Voldemort\" is an anagrammatic sobriquet for his birth name Tom Marvolo Riddle—is the archenemy of Harry Potter, who according to a prophecy has \"the power to vanquish the Dark Lord\".", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Lord", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.7606}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9041}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.8467}, {"word": "Tom Marvolo Riddle", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9948}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9969}, {"word": "Dark Lord", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7849}]}, {"text": "After killing Harry's parents, Lily and James Potter, he attempts to murder the boy, but instead leaves him with a scar on his forehead in the shape of a lightning bolt.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Lily", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "James Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}]}, {"text": "Nearly every witch or wizard dares not utter his name and refers to him instead with such monikers as \"You-Know-Who\", \"He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named\", or The Dark Lord.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "You", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9316}, {"word": "Know", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8888}, {"word": "Who", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7673}, {"word": "He", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7976}, {"word": "Named", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8388}]}, {"text": "Voldemort's obsession with blood purity signifies his aim to rid the wizarding world of Muggle (non-magical) heritage and to conquer both worlds, Muggle and wizarding, to achieve pure-blood dominance.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9645}, {"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7612}]}, {"text": "Through his mother's family, he is the last descendant of the wizard Salazar Slytherin, one of the four founders of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Salazar Slytherin", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8969}]}, {"text": "He is the leader of the Death Eaters, a group of wizards and witches dedicated to ridding the Wizarding World of Muggles and establishing Voldemort as its supreme ruler.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Eaters", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.7977}, {"word": "Wizarding World of Muggles", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8941}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.8116}]}, {"text": "Character development\nIn a 1999 interview, Rowling claimed Voldemort was invented as a nemesis for Harry Potter, and she intentionally did not flesh out Voldemort's backstory at first.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9699}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}]}, {"text": "\"The basic idea [was that Harry] didn't know he was a wizard ...", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}]}, {"text": "And so then I kind of worked backwards from that position to find out how that could be, that he wouldn't know what he was.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": []}, {"text": "When he was one year old, the most evil wizard for hundreds and hundreds of years attempted to kill him.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": []}, {"text": "He killed Harry's parents, and then he tried to kill Harry—he tried to curse him.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}]}, {"text": "Harry has to find out, before we find out.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}]}, {"text": "And—so—but for some mysterious reason the curse didn't work on Harry.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9866}]}, {"text": "So he's left with this lightning bolt-shaped scar on his forehead and the curse rebounded upon the evil wizard, who has been in hiding ever since.\"\nIn the second book, Rowling establishes that Voldemort hates non-pure-blood wizards, despite being a half-blood himself.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9869}]}, {"text": "In a 2000 interview with the BBC, Rowling described Voldemort as a self-hating bully: \"Well I think it is often the case that the biggest bullies take what they know to be their own defects, as they see it, and they put them right on someone else and then they try and destroy the other and that's what Voldemort does.\" In the same year, Rowling became more precise about Voldemort.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "BBC", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.998}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9975}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9971}]}, {"text": "She began to link him to real-life tyrants, describing him as \"a raging psychopath, devoid of the normal human responses to other people's suffering\".", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": []}, {"text": "In 2004, though, Rowling said that she did not base Voldemort on any real person.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9804}]}, {"text": "In 2006, Rowling told an interviewer that Voldemort at his core has a human fear: the fear of death.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9984}]}, {"text": "She said: \"Voldemort's fear is death, ignominious death.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9966}]}, {"text": "I mean, he regards death itself as ignominious.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": []}, {"text": "He thinks that it's a shameful human weakness, as you know.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": []}, {"text": "His worst fear is death.\"\nThroughout the series, Rowling establishes that Voldemort is so feared in the wizarding world that it is considered dangerous even to speak his name.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9971}]}, {"text": "Most characters in the novels refer to him as \"You-Know-Who\" or \"He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named\" rather than say his name aloud.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "You", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8104}, {"word": "He", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7187}, {"word": "Named", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7174}]}, {"text": "In Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, a \"taboo\" spell is placed upon the name, such that Voldemort or his followers may trace anyone who utters it.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.91}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9968}]}, {"text": "By this means, his followers eventually find and capture Harry and his friends Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Ron Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Hermione Granger", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "In the second book, Rowling reveals that I am Lord Voldemort is an anagram of the character's birth name, Tom Marvolo Riddle (in translated editions of the book, his middle name or entire birth name is/are often changed in order to allow anagrams to be formed in other languages).", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9386}, {"word": "Tom Marvolo Riddle", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9953}]}, {"text": "According to the author, Voldemort's name is an invented word.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9979}]}, {"text": "The name Voldemort is derived from the French vol de mort which means \"flight of death\" or \"theft of death\".", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.834}, {"word": "French", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9996}]}, {"text": "Appearances\n\nHarry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\n\nVoldemort makes his debut in Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9951}, {"word": "the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8523}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.982}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9724}]}, {"text": "In this story, Rowling introduces him as the Dark Lord who tried to kill Harry Potter because the boy was prophesied to destroy him.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Dark Lord", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9627}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}]}, {"text": "Voldemort murdered Harry's parents, James and Lily, but as a result of his mother's love and willingness to sacrifice herself for him, baby Harry survived when Voldemort tried to murder him with a Killing Curse.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9183}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "James", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Lily", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9979}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.976}, {"word": "Curse", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8471}]}, {"text": "Voldemort was disembodied, and Harry was left with a mysterious, lightning bolt-shaped scar on his forehead as a result.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9816}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "In the book, Voldemort unsuccessfully tries to regain his dissolved body by stealing the titular Philosopher's Stone.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8685}]}, {"text": "To achieve his objective, Voldemort uses Professor Quirrell's aid by latching onto the back of the latter's head.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9948}, {"word": "Quirrell", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9903}]}, {"text": "However, at the climax of the book, Harry manages to prevent Voldemort from stealing the stone.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9886}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets\nIn the second installment, Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, Rowling introduces Voldemort's true identity, former Hogwarts pupil and Slytherin prefect Tom Marvolo Riddle, who appears as a manifestation of the Dark Lord's teenage self that resides inside a magical diary found by Ginny Weasley.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9532}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9159}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.7916}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9629}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9958}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8577}, {"word": "Slytherin", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9752}, {"word": "Tom Marvolo Riddle", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Dark Lord", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.785}, {"word": "Ginny Weasley", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}]}, {"text": "In this book, Ginny is written as a shy girl with a crush on Harry.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Ginny", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "Feeling anxious and lonely, she begins to write into the diary and shares her deepest fears with the sympathetic Tom.", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Tom", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}]}, {"text": "However, at the climax of the story, when the manifestation of Riddle rearranges the letters in his name to write \"I am Lord Voldemort\", it is revealed that Tom and the Dark Lord are just one person and that he is a descendant of one", "source": "Voldemort", "entities": [{"word": "Riddle", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9947}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.7959}, {"word": "Tom", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}]}, {"text": "Severus Snape is a fictional character in the Harry Potter series of novels by J.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Severus Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9984}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8301}]}, {"text": "In the first five novels, he is the professor of Potions at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.93}]}, {"text": "In the sixth book, he teaches Defence Against the Dark Arts, and in the seventh book he ascends to the position of headmaster before his death.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Defence Against the Dark Arts", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9971}]}, {"text": "Snape is hostile, yet heroic towards Harry Potter throughout the series; Harry eventually learns that Snape was bullied by Harry's father, James Potter, and was in love with Harry's mother, Lily Evans.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "James Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}, {"word": "Lily Evans", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9984}]}, {"text": "This causes Snape to have mixed feelings towards Harry, who resembles his father greatly, but has his mother's eyes.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "As the series progresses, Snape's character becomes more layered and enigmatic.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}]}, {"text": "A central mystery is unravelled concerning his loyalties.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": []}, {"text": "Snape dies at the hands of Lord Voldemort in the seventh book, at which time his back story is revealed.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9984}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9899}]}, {"text": "Despite his attraction to the Dark Arts and Voldemort's ideology of wizard supremacy, Snape's love for Muggle-born Lily Evans, Harry's mother, eventually compelled him to defect from the Death Eaters.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Dark Arts", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7422}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}, {"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9699}, {"word": "Lily Evans", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}, {"word": "Death Eaters", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9373}]}, {"text": "He then became a double agent for Albus Dumbledore and the Order of the Phoenix.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Albus", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8877}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9745}, {"word": "Order of the Phoenix", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9976}]}, {"text": "The fact that Lily chose James Potter, Harry's father, only fuels Snape's hostility towards Harry.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Lily", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "James Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}]}, {"text": "Snape's character has been widely acclaimed by readers and critics.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}]}, {"text": "Rowling described him as \"a gift of a character\", whose story she had known since the first book.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}]}, {"text": "Elizabeth Hand of The Washington Post explained that Snape's life \"is the most heartbreaking, surprising and satisfying of all of Rowling's achievements\".", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Elizabeth Hand", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9998}, {"word": "The Washington Post", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}]}, {"text": "Alan Rickman portrayed Snape in all eight Harry Potter films, released between 2001 and 2011.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Alan Rickman", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.998}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.988}]}, {"text": "Paapa Essiedu will portray the character in the upcoming HBO TV adaptation.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Paapa Essiedu", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "HBO TV", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7349}]}, {"text": "Character development\nIn an interview, Rowling described Snape's character as an \"antihero\".", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}]}, {"text": "She has said that she drew inspiration for Snape's character from a disliked teacher from her own childhood, and described Snape as a horrible teacher, saying the \"worst, shabbiest thing you can do\" as a teacher is to bully students.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}]}, {"text": "However, she does suggest in the books that he is generally an effective teacher.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": []}, {"text": "Although Rowling has said that Gilderoy Lockhart is her only character that she \"deliberately based on a real person\", Snape was reportedly based, at least in part, on John Nettleship, who taught Rowling chemistry and employed her mother as an assistant at Wyedean School near Chepstow.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9975}, {"word": "Gilderoy Lockhart", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9984}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}, {"word": "John Nettleship", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9926}, {"word": "Wyedean School", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.8793}, {"word": "Chepstow", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9913}]}, {"text": "Rowling based Snape's given name on \"Severus Road\" in Clapham, and his surname is borrowed from the name of a village in England.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}, {"word": "Severus Road", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9774}, {"word": "Clapham", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9984}, {"word": "England", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "In a 1999 interview and again in 2004, Rowling singled out Snape as one of her favourite characters to write.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}]}, {"text": "Rowling was less forthcoming about Snape than she was for other characters, because his true loyalties and motivations were not revealed until the final book.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9945}]}, {"text": "However, she hinted numerous times at Snape's important role, suggesting that people should \"keep their eye on Snape\".", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}]}, {"text": "In 1999, answering a question regarding Snape's love life and the redemptive pattern to his character, Rowling expressed her surprise at the foresight.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}]}, {"text": "Rowling also disclosed that after the publication of Prisoner of Azkaban, there was one female fan who guessed Snape loved Lily Potter, making Rowling wonder how she had given herself away.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Prisoner of Azkaban", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9969}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Lily Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}]}, {"text": "After the completion of the series, Rowling began to speak openly about Snape, discussing the contrast between his character arc and that of Albus Dumbledore.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Albus Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9981}]}, {"text": "Rowling said \"the series is built around [the Dumbledore and Snape storylines]\", and maintained that she always knew what Snape would turn out to be at the end and that she carefully plotted his storyline throughout the series.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9133}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9773}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9978}]}, {"text": "\"I had to drop clues all the way through because as you know in the seventh book when you have the revelation scene where everything shifts and you realise...what Snape's motivation was.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": []}, {"text": "I had to plot that through the books because at the point where you see what was really going on, it would have been an absolute cheat on the reader at that point just to show a bunch of stuff you've never seen before.\" Rowling further said in an interview that she wanted Snape to find redemption and forgiveness: \"Snape is a complicated man...he was a flawed human being, like all of us.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "Harry forgives him...Harry really sees the good in Snape ultimately...", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9971}]}, {"text": "I wanted there to be redemption.\"\n\nAppearances\n\nNovels\n\nHarry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\nSnape first appears in Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone, shortly after Harry arrives at Hogwarts.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9877}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9731}, {"word": "Harry Potter and the Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8829}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9977}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.9964}]}, {"text": "He is the school's Potions Master, though he is widely rumoured to covet the Defence Against the Dark Arts post.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Defence Against the Dark Arts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9066}]}, {"text": "Snape himself confirms the rumour in Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9942}, {"word": "Order of the Phoenix", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9962}]}, {"text": "Snape is a sinister and malicious teacher who makes frequent snide and disparaging remarks at Harry's expense.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9989}]}, {"text": "He quickly becomes the primary antagonist of the book, as Harry suspects him of plotting to steal the Philosopher's Stone, and of attempting to kill him.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9881}]}, {"text": "Only the climax of the book reveals that Professor Quirrell, in league with Lord Voldemort, is the real enemy; Snape, suspicious of Quirrell, had been looking out for Harry throughout the book.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Quirrell", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9923}, {"word": "Voldemort", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9844}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}, {"word": "Quirrell", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}]}, {"text": "In the final chapter, Dumbledore suggests that because Harry's father James had saved Snape's life when they were both students, even though the two detested each other, Snape felt responsible for Harry in return.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Dumbledore", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9948}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}, {"word": "James", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9995}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9985}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9987}]}, {"text": "As the final book reveals, this is not the full story.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": []}, {"text": "In any case, even after Quirrell's true role is revealed, Harry retains feelings of suspicion and resentment towards Snape, and their relationship remains tense.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Quirrell", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9994}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9983}]}, {"text": "Snape's behaviour and attitude towards Harry also remain unchanged.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9962}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}]}, {"text": "Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets\nSnape has a minor role in Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, where he helps Gilderoy Lockhart oversee Hogwarts's short-lived Duelling Club, but he has little interaction with the main plot.", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9921}, {"word": "Snape", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.988}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.7043}, {"word": "Chamber of Secrets", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.8774}, {"word": "Gilderoy Lockhart", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9964}, {"word": "Hogwarts", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9917}, {"word": "Duelling Club", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9954}]}, {"text": "It is while attending the Duelling Club t", "source": "Severus Snape", "entities": [{"word": "Duelling Club", "entity_group": "ORG", "score": 0.9746}]}, {"text": "Draco Malfoy is a fictional character and a major antagonist in J.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Draco Malfoy", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.996}]}, {"text": "Rowling's Harry Potter series.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9855}]}, {"text": "He is a student in Harry Potter's year belonging in the Slytherin house.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}, {"word": "Slytherin", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.888}]}, {"text": "He is frequently accompanied by his two cronies, Vincent Crabbe and Gregory Goyle, who act as henchmen.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Vincent Crabbe", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9996}, {"word": "Gregory Goyle", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}]}, {"text": "Draco is characterised as a cowardly bully who tricks and hurts people to get what he wants; he is also a cunning user of magic.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Draco", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9924}]}, {"text": "He was played by Tom Felton in the Harry Potter film series, while Lox Pratt is set to portray him in the TV series adaptation.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Tom Felton", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9997}, {"word": "Lox Pratt", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9992}]}, {"text": "Character development\nDraco serves as a foil to the hero, Harry Potter, and is loosely based on bullies Rowling encountered during her school days.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Draco", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9856}, {"word": "Harry Potter", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.996}, {"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.999}]}, {"text": "Harry first encounters Draco's snobbish bigotry after their initial encounter at Madam Malkin's.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9982}, {"word": "Madam Malkin", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9529}]}, {"text": "Rowling uses the Malfoys to introduce themes of intolerance and bigotry into a setting where people are often judged solely by their blood lineage rather than their good character or accomplishments.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9991}]}, {"text": "Draco, adhering to his family's beliefs, thinks that Muggle-born witches and wizards, which he and other characters derogatorily describe by the epithet Mudbloods, should be denied a magical education.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Draco", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9937}, {"word": "Muggle", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9977}]}, {"text": "Harry's first impression that the Wizarding community is a \"magical wonderland\" is instantly shattered.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9986}, {"word": "Wizarding", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.7785}]}, {"text": "Says Rowling, \"[Harry] found out that many people in power in the wizarding world are just as corrupt and nasty as they are in our world.\"\nMalfoy was originally named \"Draco Spungen\" in the earliest drafts of Philosopher's Stone.", "source": "Draco Malfoy", "entities": [{"word": "Rowling", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9988}, {"word": "Harry", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9993}, {"word": "Malfoy", "entity_group": "PER", "score": 0.9897}, {"word": "Draco", "entity_group": "LOC", "score": 0.7961}, {"word": "Philosopher ' s Stone", "entity_group": "MISC", "score": 0.9761}]}, {"text": "\"Spungen\" also appeared on he